### **Loh Chuan Keat**

Mobile: 97286234

Email: authorloh111@gmail.com

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Dedicated and focused corporate secretary who excels at planning, managing, prioritizing, completing tasks and activities with multi-tasking ability simultaneously. Facilitate the orientation of new Directors and assist in Director training and development. Specialize in administrative support to different sectors of busy firms. Committed to delivering high quality work with little supervision. Displays energetic, organized and professional characteristics.

### **AREAS OF EXPERTISE**

- Efficient and logical
- Insightful
- Resourceful and Knowledgeable
- Professional and mature

- Independent and self-directed
- Motivator
- People management
- Quick Listener and Problem solver

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# SBC Corporate Management Pte. Ltd. Corporate Operation Manager

**May 2017 to October 2017** 

- Reporting to the CEO, responsible for the entire sales cycle, from identifying to developing and closing deals in order to meet sales targets on new and existing accounts.
- Manage existing clients' portfolio and strategic planning
- Provide advice to clients on corporate secretarial matters.
- Manage and grow a team of effective professionals to serve clients' needs, including work review, coaching and staff development.
- Handle existing accounts and develop long term business relationship.
- Source for new potential client leads (Law firm, CPA firm and CSP etc.) and updating CRM for sales follow ups.
- Develop and execute marketing programs that support business priorities in Singapore.
- Conduct sales and service orientation to clients.
- Provide operational support at office.
- Be the liaison for regional teams to tailor South East Asia marketing campaigns and the local markets.
- Working closely with counterpart in the Hong Kong Head Office. Support Head Board Services to grow and manage corporate secretarial services
- Responsible for overall operational effectiveness of the corporate secretarial department by initiating process reviews and improvements.

# Vistra Alternative Investments (Singapore) Pte. Ltd. Funds Corporate Secretarial Associate

September 2016 to April 2017

- Establishing companies in multiple jurisdictions
- Setting up a registered office



- Assisting with post-incorporation and structure implementation
- Appointing industry qualified company directors
- Appointing a qualified chief financial officer
- Placing a company into liquidation
- Selling ready-made companies and special purpose vehicles
- Arranging Registered Office & Director Services
- Managing board meetings and circulating briefing documents
- Ensuring all statutory returns and fees are submitted
- Drafting corporate documents and agreements
- Corresponding with local authorities
- Setting up and managing a special purpose vehicle to act as an escrow agent
- Monitoring fund expenses and wire transfers, bookkeeping and reporting
- Monitoring maintenance of accounting records
- Call and Distribution Notices
- Processing subscriptions and redemptions
- Collecting and maintaining investor records
- Completing rigorous 'know your client' and anti-money laundering checks on investors
- Preparing and distributing dynamic investor statement reports

## Iyer Practice Singapore Pte. Ltd. Trust Administrator

June 2016 to September 2016

- Process and review legal and financial paperwork associated with trust fund accounts.
- Provide customer service to clients, resolve client problems, and report the status of accounts.
- Manage and set up the accounts associated with trust funds.
- Ensure trust fund accounts comply with bank and government regulations.
- Proper and efficient administration of a portfolio of fiduciary structures.
- Drafting and preparation of documents like trustee minutes, company minutes, payment instructions, account opening forms etc.
- Update and maintain database.
- Adheres to Trust & Fiduciary Company's policies and procedures.
- Ensures Compliance/Risk requirements are met for all fiduciary structures and proper escalation is raised when necessary.
- Review distribution statements to ensure distribution policy stated in the prospectus has been adhered to:
- Review financial statements to ensure appropriate disclosures are made in compliance with applicable guidelines and accounting principles
- Prepare and maintain compliance checklists for each of the new REITs/trusts on-boarded;
- Check for and ensure compliance with provisions in the Trust Deed and Prospectus:
- Client servicing and management
- Drafting and ensuring that Operating Memorandums are in place.

### Baker Tilly FFW LLP Senior Associate

November 2015 to May 2016

Independently handling the secretarial matters of 130 Singapore private companies and 20 offshore companies.

- Familiar with drafting of various resolutions i.e, incorporation, change of shareholders, appointment and resignation of directors/secretary, establishment of bank accounts and facilities, striking off, allot and issue shares, transfer shares, S&P agreements, loan agreements, rental agreements etc.
- Maintains and update the statutory records of the companies. i.e Register of Members, Directors, Allotments, Transfers, Share certificates, Proxy Forms, Minutes and resolution.
- Participate in financing projects and complete banks' KYC requirements.
- Management of bank transactions and correspondence.
- Manage all communication with clients, overseas colleagues, banks, authorities etc. according to clients' requirement.
- Annual compliance work including holding of AGM and filing of Annual Returns with ACRA and maintenance of statutory registers and minute book for inspection.
- Adept with ACRA filing/research/extract information/use of website.
- Act and provide company secretary work for Companies registered in Singapore.
- Secretarial support for public listed companies.

## Inter-trust Singapore Corporate Secretarial & Accounting Services 2010 to October 2015 Senior Associate

- Independently handling the secretarial matters of 80 Singapore private companies and 10 offshore companies.
- Familiar with drafting of various resolutions i.e, incorporation, change of shareholders, appointment and resignation of directors/secretary, establishment of bank accounts and facilities, striking off, allot and issue shares, transfer shares, S&P agreements, loan agreements, rental agreements etc.
- Maintains and update the statutory records of the companies. i.e Register of Members, Directors, Allotments, Transfers, Share certificates, Proxy Forms, Minutes and resolution.
- Participate in financing projects and complete banks' KYC requirements.
- Management of bank transactions and correspondence.
- Manage all communication with clients, overseas colleagues, banks, authorities etc. according to clients' requirement.
- Annual compliance work including holding of AGM and filing of Annual Returns with ACRA and maintenance of statutory registers and minute book for inspection.
- Adept with ACRA filing/research/extract information/use of website.
- Act and provide company secretary work for Companies registered in Singapore.
- Secretarial support for public listed companies.

# Standard Chartered Bank, Malaysia Sales Executive

2008 - 2010

- Possess 2 years of working experience in mortgage sales
- Strong verbal and written communication sales
- Demonstrated relational management and new business development skills
- Extensive knowledge of mortgage services, products, operations and current market trends
- Effective management and leadership skills
- Dynamic, Flexible and ability to motivate a team
- Good networking and relationship building skills

- Well verse in internet explorer and Microsoft software
- Actively participated in the unit sales planning and generated unit action plans for exceeding and achieving sales target
- Prepared and gathered all accurate sales reports related activities
- Generated new business via outdoor/outbound marketing calls, local sales promotions, seminars and presentations
- Structured transactions of deals based on customers requirements
- Conduct diligence to ensure quality of the customer before acquisition
- Recruits and trains new mortgage staff
- Identifies and meets up with customer requirements
- Pursue and develop opportunities to meet new clients

### Bintang Maju, Malaysia Sales Supervisor

2001-2008

- Ability to leverage networks by cultivating key industry related relationships
- Observant and responsive to market trend and customer demand, giving feedback, roll out initiatives, and make recommendations on merchandising and product presentation
- Quick learner who can absorb new ideas, able to communicate clearly and effectively
- Able to quickly build a rapport with customers
- Strong desire to exceed customer expectations
- Flexible, open to ideas and willing to learn
- Keeping abreast of market trends and being aware of competitors
- Able to handle complaints, aggressive customers and difficult situations
- Monitor the inventory so that able to bring in the stock necessary and prevent overstocking
- Responsible for sales staff retention, development and job satisfaction levels.
- Supervise, lead and motivate a team
- Guide the team to focus on building long lasting relationship with customer
- Proactive and able to use initiative when solving problems
- Develop marketing strategies and promotion activities
- Promote branding and company
- Able to handle difficult situation and challenging clients
- Merchandise and inventory management, growing the sales, day-to-day operations, staff performance management and development
- To implement and control the appropriate/effective strategies in order to achieve sales targets and to maximize profits - to improve productivity and accelerate growth.

#### RESPONSIBILITIES FROM PAST WORK HISTORY

- The general management and retail operations of the business unit and maintaining a smooth flow of work between departments.
- Identify growth areas and tighten gaps; implement sales strategies, business plans, forecast and budgets, and achieving results with a view of P & L.
- Effectively communicate company's objectives and ensure retail and sales teams have clear goals and objectives on the customer experience and productivity targets.
- Review effectiveness of Marketing activities; sales productivity and individual sales team member's performance on a regular basis.

- Provide team leadership through open communication, training, mentoring/ coaching and active encouragement to meet and exceed goals.
- Ensure that VM is consistent and coherent with brands' guidelines and visual merchandising standards.
- To manage and support in working with the relevant parties (both internal & external) for building new stores and set-ups, when such occasion arises.
- Responsible for inventory management and planning of suitable merchandise mix for each POS.
- Responsible for pricing strategies and responsible for achieving company KPI.
- Compilation of monthly reports to analyze sales trends and profitability of products, product management proposals and market/competitor survey and observations.
- Develop and implement strategic marketing plans, sales plans and forecasts to achieve corporate objectives for sales & marketing services; manages operating budgets for the department.
- Ensure effective control of marketing results and take corrective action to guarantee the achievement of marketing objectives fall within designated budgets.
- Evaluate market research and adjusts marketing strategy to meet changing market competitive conditions and monitors competitors' products sales and marketing activities
- Establish and maintain relationships with industry influencers and key strategic partners
- Guide preparation of marketing activity reports and present to executive management
- maintains a consistent corporate image throughout all product lines, promotional materials and events
- Direct sales forecasting activities and sets performance goals (KPIs) accordingly, responsible for managing staffing, training and performance evaluations to develop and control sales and marketing programs
- Direct market channel development activity and coordinates sales distribution by establishing sales territories, quotas and goals; represents company at trade association meetings to promote product
- Meet with key clients, maintaining relationships, negotiating and closing deals; analysis and control expenditure of sales & marketing department to conform to budgetary requirements
- Preparation of sales and marketing standard operations procedure and periodic sales report showing sales volume, potential sales and areas of proposed client base expansion
- Review and analyze sales and marketing performance against programs, quotes and plans to determine effectiveness.

#### SKILLS

- Analytical Skill
- Ability to think strategically
- Innovative, thinks out of the box
- Social ease with a good sense of humor
- Great communication and interpersonal skills
- Professional verbal/written communication skills
- Flexible and adaptable to work, changes and challenges
- Ability to leverage networks by cultivating key industry related relationships
- Experienced in observing tact and discretion, for dealing with confidential information

### **EDUCATION**

SAICSA Executive Diploma in Corporate Administration (EDCA) – Singapore Association of the Institute of Chartered secretaries and administrators (SAICSA)

### **TRAINING**

Entry Level Program, Global Inter-trust Academy April, 2014
Inter-trust, Amsterdam

### OTHER POINTS OF INTEREST

Socializing, playing musical instruments, traveling, exercising, debating, reading and etc...

### **DETAILS**

Date of birth: 4 March 1982 Citizenship: Malaysian Current: SPR

Languages: English language, Conversational Chinese and dialects

### **EXPECTED SALARY**

SGD5,700